STEVENURMSTON

www.clearbar.com steve@clearbar.com 07590843170 @steveu

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I'm a passionate designer and developer with over 8 years experience creating websites and applications for businesses both large and small.

Comfortable in user research, visual design & technical development, with the communication skills to be effective between the lines.

EDUCATION

The University of York

MSc (with Distinction) in Human Centred Interactive Technologies, 2008 – 2009

The University of Glasgow

MA (2.1) in Political Science, 2000 – 2004

Bootham School York

A-Levels in Art (B), History (B), Geography (B) & 10 GCSEs

WORK EXPERIENCE

Interaction Designer at Designition

November 2009 – Present
I try to take a broader role in many projects, alongside filling in gaps with visual design, and front and backend code. I also enjoy taking unusual projects from start to finish.

Senior Designer at Designition

June 2005 – September 2008

Primarily responsible for visual design and front-end development, but also involved throughout projects; client meetings, proposal writing, project management, information architecture and CMS development.

Self Employed at Clearbar

January 2004 – December 2005

Managed to keep the wolves at bay whilst teaching myself to make websites. Learnt a lot from both technical and business standpoints, and consistently managed to produce quality work on time.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Expert skills in cross-platform web development using HTML/CSS, Object-oriented PHP, MySQL and JavaScript.

Developing skills in Node.js, Ruby (Rails), and iOS development.
Highly proficient in Photoshop, various text editors, and Omnigraffle.

Happy using Mac OS, Git and Terminal. Comfortable using Windows.

AWARDS & RECOGNITION

Received a fully funded ESRPC scholarship to study at the University of York.

York Minster won Best Tourism Website at the Yorkshire Tourist Board White Rose Awards 2007.

York England won Best Business-To-Business at the Yorkshire Digital Awards 2007.